smartsavvyliving.com 2019-03-31

# Disclosure and Privacy Policies

### Love this post? Share it with your friends:

Smart Savvy Living found at https://smartsavvyliving.com.com/ (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”).

This policy is valid from 8 April 2013 and last updated 4 May 2018.

This website is written and edited by me, Michelle Pegram, along with various contributors. For questions about this website, please contact Michelle at [SmartSavvyLiving@gmail.com](mailto:smartsavvyliving@gmail.com).

Smart Savvy Living posts paid and non-paid posts, advertisements, and sponsored giveaways. Smart Savvy Living receives cash and other services and forms of compensation while providing reviews, hosting giveaways, and marketing products and services. Any time payment of any kind is received, it is disclosed at the beginning of the sponsored post.

Smart Savvy Living is also an affiliate of many products and companies you may see featured in posts and banners on this site, however, Smart Savvy Living and any contributors will ALWAYS publish 100% HONEST opinions in any form of post or communication and any opinion posted is purely the contributor’s own. Michelle and any other contributors thoroughly believe in maintaining integrity and honesty even if compensated for our time.

This website does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

As a reader of Smart Savvy Living, you are taking any information that Smart Savvy Living supplies at your own risk. Any information provided here is for entertainment purposes only and Smart Savvy Living is not providing any medical, legal, or other professional advice.

Unless otherwise noted, Smart Savvy Living is the legal copyright holder of the material on this website and it may not be used, reprinted, or published without our written consent. You may provide post titles and one photo that you then link to the corresponding post on Smart Savvy Living, but any content and/or photos may not be used without prior written consent. See more details on our [FAQ page](https://smartsavvyliving.com/frequently-asked-questions/).

Smart Savvy Living is not responsible for the actions of advertisers or sponsors of this website. If you win a sponsored giveaway or contest at Smart Savvy Living, we cannot be held responsible for any problems with the giveaway prize including malfunctions or unreceived prizes. If you purchase or try a product or service based on a review or link at Smart Savvy Living, you must take action with that company to resolve any issues, not Smart Savvy Living.

Smart Savvy Living’s giveaways and contests are in no way associated with Facebook, Twitter, or any other entity unless otherwise directly specified in said giveaway or contest.

Any person that enters a contest or giveaway on Smart Savvy Living are stating that they are a legal resident of any countries the giveaway or contest may be open to and are 18+ or equal legal age to enter said contests or giveaways in their place of residence.

Smart Savvy Living reserves the right to change the focus of this website, shut it down, sell it, or to change any terms of use at Smart Savvy Living’s discretion.

Smart Savvy Living is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com, endless.com, smallparts.com or myhabit.com.

**Privacy Policy:**

Last updated 4 May 2018

Smart Savvy Living will not put your email on spam lists or sell your information to other companies. This includes email addresses submitted via newsletter requests and giveaways.

If there happens to be a special exception, you will be thoroughly alerted prior to submitting your email.

Any submitted addresses or other personal information due to giveaway and contest wins will only be used to give to the sponsors so that they may send you your prize. However, Smart Savvy Living cannot be held responsible or know what the sponsor may do with your information after receiving it.  Smart Savvy Living is not responsible for the privacy practices of advertisers or website commenters. Any information contributors to Smart Savvy Living collect will only be used for private contact such as in the event of needing to confirm a giveaway win.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.smartsavvyliving.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/opt_out.asp)

_Smartsavvyliving.com uses Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using Google’s  [Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads%E2%80%8E%3Cbr%20/%3E%3Cbr%20/%3E%3Cbr%20/%3E%3Cbr%20/%3E%3Cbr%20/%3E%3Cbr%20/%3E%3Cbr%20/%3E) page. Users can completely block Google Analytics tracking using[Google’s Opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)._

**Notice Regarding Online Behavioral Advertising**  
We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information  
when you visit our Web site.  These companies may use non-personally identifiable information  
(e.g. click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked  
or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide  
advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you.  These  
companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information.  To learn  
more about this behavioral advertising practice visit the NAI at [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.smartsavvyliving.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/www.networkadvertising.org).  To  
opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.smartsavvyliving.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/choices).

**What information do we collect? How is it used?**

**Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website** : We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

**Automatically-Collected Information** : We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

**Cookies** : We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.  
Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet.  
Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

**What do we use your information for?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  * To operate, maintain, and improve our website  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)
  * To improve customer service and respond to your comments and inquiries.  
(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity
  * To send periodic emails such as newsletters. The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Google Analytics – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

MailerLite – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to MailerLites’s privacy policy for further information.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

ANONYMOUS DATA

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION

If you create a user profile on the Website or leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible.  To create a user profile, you must choose a username and password and input your email address for profile confirmation.  Your email address will never be available publicly.  At your option, you may also add an avatar, a profile description, and a link to your website.

You may also choose to link your Facebook, Instagram, and Google Account.

Users may see your username, avatar, profile description and website information.

**How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access your personal information.

**Do we use cookies?**

Yes. The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

ADVERTISING

**Display Ads**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

**Retargeting  Ads**

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

**Affiliate Program Participation**

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Smart Savvy Living is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

Newsletters

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at smartsavvyliving@gmail.com to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to smartsavvyliving@gmail.com.

Amend – You may contact us at smartsavvyliving@gmail.com.com to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to smartsavvyliving@gmail.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

CHILDREN’S INFORMATION

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at webmaster@foodfanatic.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

**Online Privacy Policy Only**

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

**Your Consent**

By using our site, you consent to our web site privacy policy.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and update the Privacy Policy modification date at the top of this page.

CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions, please email us at [smartsavvyliving@gmail.com](mailto:smartsavvyliving@gmail.com).

### Love this post? Share it with your friends:
